ALEXSON ROY: So what we're going to talk about now is maybe chronic issues that a lot of athletes deal with.
And once again, it all has to do with the joint issues, okay?
So there's a number of issues that a lot of athletes deal with.
One of 'em, okay, that a lot of football players have to deal with is issues to their spine, which is--which begins in the neck because there's a lot of contact, there's a lot of blows that they take to the neck.
They kinda concave like all of these vertebras from the base of the neck to the shoulder.
So from that, they have a lot of shoulder issues.
Okay?
And then, you have--let's say, your baseball players.
If you're a pitcher, most likely, you're going to throw your rotator cuff out, and most of, you know, your upper back is going to be affected by that.
And if you're a power lifter, okay?
You're going to have a lot of lower back issues, okay, and that has to do with your hips, and kinda like putting a lot of load on your core.
And then, the other issue is with a lot of golfers and tennis players, they have problems with their elbows.
And there's actually a condition called "tennis elbow" that when you do your back swing, it has to do with all the muscles that contribute to your back swing, and then with golfers, you're swinging forward.
So within the elbow, there's a point there which is called your epicondyle, and this is medial, which is inside, is affected with that.
And then you have your runners, okay?
Hamstrings is definitely a problem.
Everything down here, like below your glute, inside your thighs.
And then with soccer players, it's your shins, okay, the part on the other side of your calf 'cause you're being kicked all the time in your shin.
And with running constantly in soccer, that area gets really tense.
And so what we're going to do today is we're going to focus on just some of these issues that I talked about as far as conditions that have to do with sports-related injuries, okay?
So we're going to focus on four main issues today.